<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tils on Welcome</title><link>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/</link><description>Recent content in Tils on Welcome</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 20:44:42 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.arnevogel.com/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TIL: Japan APN Sim Einrichten</title><link>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/japan-apn-sim-einrichten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 20:44:42 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/japan-apn-sim-einrichten/</guid><description>Kleiner Eintrag, weil es bei mir nicht so einfach war die APN SIM auf Android einzurichten.
Ein Paar Sachen die zu beachten sind:
Zumindestens bei mir: In den Einstellung wird nichts zu APN gefunden. Auf Deutsch heißt das bei mir Zugangspunkte Die Zugangspunkte können unter Einstellungen &amp;gt; Verbindungen &amp;gt; Mobile Netzwerke eingestellt werden. Von hier aus funktioniert die englische Anleitung wieder</description></item><item><title>TIL: Randomness in Latex</title><link>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/randomness-in-latex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 21:48:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/randomness-in-latex/</guid><description>You can use \usepackage{pgffor} for randomness in LaTeX.
\usepackage{pgffor} \pgfmathdeclarerandomlist{Options}{{option1}{option3}{option3}} \pgfmathrandomitem{\randomlySelected}{Options} This will select one random element from Options and populate \randomlySelected with it. \randomlySelected can they get used just as you would expect it to work. One thing I noticed though: the random item selection will pick the same element for ~15 seconds. So rebuilding will not necessarily give you another option, even if you rebuild multiple times, if you don&amp;rsquo;t wait for some amount of time.</description></item><item><title>TIL: Window Resize Behavior on Mobile</title><link>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/window-resize-behavior-on-mobile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 11:44:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/window-resize-behavior-on-mobile/</guid><description>When the url bar on mobile gets hidden it triggers a window.resize. This is something I learned by a PR for listudy.
In my code I had window.onresize = resize_ground; to adjust the size of the chess board when the browser window changed width. But as Sean Yeh in the PR pointed out this caused unintended behavior in mobile browsers. When scrolling down the url bar would hide. As this would trigger a window.</description></item><item><title>TIL: Beamer has Slide Transitions</title><link>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/beamer-slide-transitions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 16:12:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/beamer-slide-transitions/</guid><description>I always just assumed that slide transition animations are limited to WYSIWYG presentation programs. Turns out you can define slide transitions in beamer by default without any special packages.
See Chapter 14.3 of the beamer documentation for all the available transitions and their options.
Some of the transitions seem to be wonky though, with some parts of the slide being hidden or cut off after the transition.</description></item><item><title>TIL: The Nix Home Manager Works on Non-Nix Distros</title><link>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/nix-home-manager-works-on-non-nix-distros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 16:47:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.arnevogel.com/til/nix-home-manager-works-on-non-nix-distros/</guid><description>Nix in general seems promising for both reproducible software and as a distro. But making a full switch seems like a lot of work and im lazy. Because of this I am happy to find out that the home-manager project works on non-nix distros. Tl:dr on home-manager: it lets you configure and install software on your system using the nix ecosystem. This lets me incrementally switch while staying on my regular distros.</description></item></channel></rss>